Apps[Support](https://steps.app/en/support)[Blog](https://steps.app/en/blog)[Jobs](https://steps.app/en/jobs)

### Explore

### our apps

[

Pedometer

Step Counter and Walking Tracker](https://steps.app/en/)[

Habits

Build powerful, life-changing routines](https://steps.app/en/habit-tracker)[

Fitbit Sync

Sync your Fitbit data to Apple Health](https://steps.app/en/fitbitsync)

Privacy Policy
==============

We at StepsApp respect your privacy. We are glad to tell you more about which data is accessed, how it is used, and which services we use to enhance your StepsApp experience.
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

### 1.0 Data Controller and Owner

StepsApp GmbH  
Karmeliterplatz 4c  
8010 Graz  
Austria  

### 2.0 How we visualize your activity data

StepsApp analyzes your iPhone’s built-in pedometer data to generate our visual graphs and to calculate your daily burned calories. In no case is your personal data ever transferred to a third party. It is exclusively stored on your device within the application container of StepsApp.  
If you choose to have StepsApp integrate with Apple Health, the app will have access only to the health data types you opt-in to access as described in Sections 2.1 of this Privacy Policy. The data read from Apple Health is used solely for visualizing your data within the app. It is not collected or disclosed outside of your local installation of the app. If you opt-in, StepsApp can also write your active energy, height, and weight to Apple Health.

#### 2.1 Apple HealthKit

HealthKit is an activity data handling service provided by Apple Inc. that enables you to access or store activity data.  

#### 2.2 Challenges

If you opt in to participate in one of our challenges, you agree that your anonymous activity data is securely uploaded to our servers. Note that you can opt out of this at any point by disagreeing with the respective terms of service in the app's settings. Further you can always contact us if you want all of your anonymous data to be removed from our servers completely. We do not share any data with any third party or partners.

### 3.0 How we try to make StepsApp even better

We use analytics services as described in Sections 3.1, 3.2 and 3.3 of this Privacy Policy that help us understand how StepsApp is being used. The processing of your personal data takes place in compliance with the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”). We do not share any personal or Apple Health Kit data.

**Usage Information**  
We collect information about your activity on our services, for instance how you use them (such as frequency, duration of usage, app crashes, features you've been using, advertising that you click on).

**Device information**  
We collect information from and about the device(s) you use to access our services, including:

* hardware and software information such as IP address, device ID and type, device-specific and apps settings and characteristics, app crashes, app version, app name, type of user (pro/free), browser type, version and language, operating system, time zones, identifiers associated with cookies or other technologies that may uniquely identify your device or browser (e.g., IMEI/UDID and MAC address).
* information on your wireless and mobile network connection, like your service provider and signal strength.

#### 3.1 Google Analytics

Google Analytics is an analytics service provided by Google, Inc.  

#### 3.2 Email & Support

The only situation we may get access to your personal identifiable information (PII) is when you personally decide to email us your feedback or to provide us with a bug report. The PII we may get from you in that situation are strictly limited to your name, email address and the contents of your response only. In above situation, we guarantee that your PII will only be used for contacting you and improving our services. We will never use such information (e.g. your name and email address) for any other purposes, such as to further market our products, or to disclose your personal information to a third party for commercial gains.

#### 3.3 Ads

StepsApp displays ads within our app through a third party ad network (Gravite). These ads are served by this third-party ad networks. StepsApp Pro members are not shown any ads. You can enable and disable personalized ads within our app at any time. Personalized ads are by default disabled for residents of the European Union, Switzerland and United Kingdom.  

#### 3.4 Meta and Google Ads

For some of our products, we compare limited user data with Meta Ads and Google Ads users who click on our ads on in that platform. We do this in order to measure how successful our app install campaigns are on that platform. Further information on how Meta and Google processes personal data, including the legal basis Meta and Google relies on and the ways to exercise your data subject rights with Meta and Google, can be found here:  

#### 3.5 Sentry

StepsApp uses Sentry, an application monitoring solution designed to identify, monitor, and alert us to errors, bugs, and other performance issues that are occurring within our applications. If an app crashes during normal use, information about the crash (such as the time of the crash, the device model, operating system version, and the state of the application at the time of the crash) will be sent to the servers of Sentry.  

### 4.0 Cookies and other similar data collection technologies

As described in Sections 3.0 of this Privacy Policy, we sometimes work with third parties to deliver ads or offers. Sometimes we or these third parties do so through a mobile "SDK." The SDK is a bit of computer code that app developers can include in their apps to enable data to be collected and ads to be shown. We may use this and similar technology to deliver certain advertising through mobile applications and browsers based on data associated with your mobile device, and we may work with third parties who likewise embed their SDKs into our services, for third party advertising. If you'd like to opt-out from having ads tailored to you in this way on your mobile device, please follow the instructions below.

If you wish to opt out of interest-based cross-application tracking through your mobile device, you can do so through your device "settings", as follows (but please note that the below is for informational purposes only and Apple, Google, or other device platforms may change the manner in which their "opt out" settings work at any time): Please note that if you opt out through these settings, you will continue to receive advertising after you opt-out, but it may not be tailored to your interests. For instance, that advertising may be based on your real-time or "contextual" application usage or general location inferred from IP address.

#### 4.1 Opting out

Interest-based, cross-application tracking is disabled by default on all devices running iOS 14.5 or newer. If you are running an older version of iOS, you can always disabled it in the iOS preferences under “Privacy“. If you have StepsApp version 6.0 or newer, you can also opt out of interest-based, cross-app advertising directly from the "Privacy Policy" section in the StepsApp settings.

More information on our use of cookies on our websites can be found in our [Cookie Policy](http://steps.app/privacy?os=web).

### 5.0 Social Media

We maintain a presence on several social networking and blogging platforms, such as Facebook, Instagram, Google, WordPress, LinkedIn, TikTok and Twitter. We may incorporate some third-party social networking features into our Services (including, allowing users to interact with others and share certain content and information on social media platforms) or utilize third-party provided platforms to publish or manage the Services or portions thereof. Through these platforms and features, we receive or may share information about you, and this Privacy Policy applies to that information as well. In addition, some providers of third-party social media or blogging platforms we utilize have their own privacy policies which explain how the third parties that provide them may collect, use and protect your information (e.g., if you establish an account with such platform providers directly). By using social features, you agree to those third parties’ privacy policies and terms of use.

If you choose to communicate with us or another user through social features available on our websites or mobile applications or through our social media pages, or other similar communication or messaging features or services, such information may be made publicly available. For security purposes, please do not include any password, social security number, payment card or other sensitive information via these features. We have the right, but not the obligation to monitor messages and communications between and among users for security and training purposes. We may, but are not obligated to, remove any content we deem inappropriate.

### 6.0 Children's Privacy

Our services are intended for general audiences over the age of 13 years old (or over the age of 16 if you are resident in the EEA). We do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 years old, or 16 years old in the EEA. If you are not over 13 years old (or 16 years old in the EEA) then DO NOT DOWNLOAD OR USE THE SERVICES.

### 7.0 Last Updated

This Privacy Policy was last modified on April 26, 2023.

If you have any questions regarding privacy, or have questions about our practices, please contact us via email at [info@steps.app](mailto:info@steps.app)

StepsApp Pedometer App — Step Counter and Walking Tracker

20+ Million users already enjoy StepsApp.  
StepsApp turns your iPhone into a simple and beautiful step counter.  
Just put your phone in your pocket and off you go. Set goals. Count steps. Burn calories.

© 2015-2024 StepsApp GmbH
